What if I say daily.number of wheels equals three, and I copy and paste these two print statements?
Right, for the class that's still four, but now for this specific instance, and I should say for this instance daily.
Now the number of wheels is three, right?
Okay.
So inheritance, let me close this Rebel window.
I have my class vehicle. Let's make a new class.
And we don't necessarily want the vehicle class to tell us how many number of wheels it has.
That's more of an implementation detail. So I'm going to take that away for now.
Instead, I'm going to make two new classes. I'm going to make a class car vehicle, and inherit from vehicle.
And it's going to have a number of wheels equals four.
This is the last time when I showed you inheritance. I showed making a new init method for that child's class.
But I don't need one here. If I don't provide an init method in the subclass, which initializers are going to use.
If there's no init method here, it'll just call the init method for vehicle.
In the same way that we saw if the vehicle has a variable, it's available to all of its subclasses.
Same thing for methods. Python will try to instantiate the car if it doesn't see it.
It'll look for the init on vehicle, and it'll just be that very single one.
And let's say we have a class truck. It's also a vehicle.
And the truck has six wheels.
And it's also, these trucks run on diesel. So this time, let's make a custom constructor.
I'll say a definite pass-in-self. I'll take a make model.
And the fuel will be diesel.
This time, I want to call the init on super. Why is that?
Looking at the fuel here, and the fuel here, why is that?
We need to override that value.
Yeah, I'm overwriting this default value.
And so to super.init, we're going to pass in the make, the model, and the fuel.
Okay, now let's take a look at this.
I want to show you something that's not in the class website, but is a pretty cool feature of Python.
I can do, I can open up my Python tab here in VS code.
And if we press the up key, we'll see that this is the command that VS code automatically filled in to run my script.
So it's got the full path to my Python 3 virtual environment.
And then it's got the full path to my file.
I don't necessarily need all of that.
I can just say a Python in my virtual environment and pass in the path like that.
Oops, sorry, and I'll need to comment out my old code here because the vehicle is the same.
The vehicle no longer has the number of wheels.
Handy shortcut to come in out, a bunch of lines in VS code.
At least for OS X, you can just select them and press command forward slash.
And if you select, comment it out code and press it again, it'll uncomment it.
Okay, let's try that again.
Okay, this works.
A really cool thing that Python can do is called run in interactive mode.
So it's great for debugging and it's not in the course website.
So if you want to know this right at down, all you need to do is pass the dash i flag after Python before your script.
What this is going to do is run everything in this Python file and it'll drop you in a ripple.
So you can take take a look at, you know, the state of everything.
I see here that I made the daily variable.
Now I can look at that.
Right in my ripple.
So really nifty thing to know when you're just debugging.
Now I'm going to show you some of our new instances.
I'm going to say my daily driver is a car and it's a Subaru.
The make is a cross track.
And now I can print out an upstream.
I drive daily.make.
Daily.model.
It uses daily.fuel.
And drives on.
Daily.num.
Weels.
Okay.
What did I do here?
I don't know.
Number of wheels.
I asked number.
Thank you.
Okay.
There we go.
Driver Subaru cross track uses gas has four wheels.
I can do the same thing for a truck.
I can say my truck is a Ford F350.
So awesome cool truck.
I can check the truck.
Make truck model.
What's the truck fuel going to be?
Yes.
It's not gas.
So if I look at where I.
Oh, that's okay.
So my truck fuel is going to be diesel.
All my trucks are going to be diesel.
Pretty useful, right?
Using type is instance and is subclass.
So the type of my truck is a truck.
The type of my daily driver.
Oh, I really can't type today.
There is no truck method here.
That is type of daily.
Okay.
So it's a car.
I can ask is instance.
Daily.
Car.
Well, I get.
Yeah, true, right?
Is instance.
Truck.
Yeah.
And just to side note here, I know that this truck is my lower case variable.
My instance.
And I know that this capital T truck is my class.
Kind of just by looking at it from naming convention, right?
It's one of the reasons that conventions and Python are so powerful.
Awesome.
Now, I want to ask.
Is subclass truck.
Vehicle.
Yep.
And is subclass car.
Vehicle.
Yeah.
What about is subclass of vehicle and car?
Nope.